

SHERAZ SABIR

Chemical Engineer

PROFILE

Resourceful Chemical Engineer special interest in Production of Quality Products using engineering techniques. Combine knowledge of chemistry and product design to create functional products and manufacturing equipment. Fabricate prototypes, collect testing data, run statistical analysis, and redesign as necessary. Ensure products comply with industry safety standards. Conduct research within consumer base to determine gaps in market and identify desirable characteristics for new products.

CONTACT

ADDRESS:

R-61, 15 A/4 Bufferzone, North Karachi, Karachi.

PHONE:

+923360800544

EMAIL:

sherazsabirss@gmail.com

EDUCATION

NED UNIVERSITY OF ENGINEERING AND TECHNOLOGY

2013 - 2017

[Chemical Engineering. Final Year Project on Synthesis of Silicone Based Grease which should be thermally stable up to 200°C and made a Process flow diagram and fabricate the main component of the Plant Design and make the best Optimization]

GOVERNMENT DEHLI COLLEGE

2011 - 2013

[Pre-Engineering with 83%]

SHOEBY GRAMMAR SEC. SCHOOL

2001 - 2011

[Science with 85%]

WORK EXPERIENCE

•LIBERTY MILLS LIMITED • • COMPLIANCE OFFICER •

FEB 2018-Present

Looking after the whole Chemical Management. Ensure the Compliance of MRSL/RSL of Different Standards. Perform Internal Audits on a regular basis and make sure the proper handling of Chemicals and ensure the proper use of PPEs through training.

•GUL AHMED TEXTILE MILL• •INTERN•

MAY 2016-JUNE 2016

Engaged with Waste Water Treatment Plant and Laboratory. Performed Raw Material Testing Especially Chemicals. Titled as the "Hard Working & Passionate" by Lab Manager.

•CAPTAIN PQ CHEMICALS• •INTERN•

MAY 2015-JUNE 2015

Worked under Plant Manager and Quality Control Manager. Perform Raw Material Testing and Finish Product. Involved with RO Plant operations and performed Water testing.

SKILLS

